apptivo.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy - Apptivo

**Updated on July 29, 2019**

**1\. Introduction**

The U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission have agreed on a framework of data protection principles and supplemental principles to enable U.S. companies to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data transferred from the EEA to the U.S. (“EU-U.S. Privacy Shield”). Apptivo highly respects the privacy of its customers, business partners and employees and recognizes the requirement for appropriate protection and proper management of personal information provided. Apptivo on behalf of itself and its wholly owned U.S. domiciled entities, has made a decision to voluntarily adhere to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles recognized by the EEA as providing adequate data protection. Apptivo complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as agreed upon between the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission regarding the collection, usage, retention and removal of personal information from European Union member countries. Apptivo certifies that it adheres to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for onward transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose limitation, Access, Recourse, Enforcement and Liability as well as the Supplemental Principles of the Framework.

To learn more about the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield program, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

**Apptivo adheres to all the mentioned Privacy Shield Principles.**

In case there is any conflict between the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield principles and this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield principles will prevail. This Policy outlines the general practices for implementing the requirements of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield in connection with personal data that is transferred from the EEA to the U.S.: including the types of information that is collected and transferred; how it is used; and, the choices individuals located in the EEA have regarding the use of, and their ability to correct, that information.

**2\. Scope**

This Privacy Policy applies to all Apptivo U.S. operations, divisions and subsidiaries as far as personal information from the EEA is received in any format whatsoever, including electronic, paper or oral transmission. This Policy also applies to entities which handle and process EEA personal data on behalf of Apptivo.

This privacy statement describes how APPTIVO INC. collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: [www.apptivo.com](https://www.apptivo.com/) . It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you should first contact us at [privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com)

**2.1 Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information such as, Name, E-mail address, Mailing Address, Phone number
  * Billing Information such as, Credit Card number and Billing Address.
  * Unique Identifiers such as User name, Account number, Passwords
  * Preferences Information such as Product wish lists, Order history, Marketing preferences
  * Information about your business such as Company name, Company size, Business type.

As is true of most Web sites, we automatically gather information about your computer such as your IP address, browser type, referring/exit pages, and operating system.

**2.2 We use this information to**

  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you order confirmation
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send product updates or warranty information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you catalogs
  * Send you newsletters
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our Website and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Display content based upon your interests
  * Choice/Opt-Out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at [ privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com).

**3\. Information Sharing**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may share your personal information with companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information

  * As required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
  * If APPTIVO INC. is involved in a merger, acquisition or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

**3.1 Sharing with trusted third parties**

We may share your personal data with affiliated companies within our corporate family, with third parties with which we have partnered to allow you to integrate their services into our own Services, and with trusted third party service providers as necessary for them to perform services on our behalf.

We only share your personal data as necessary for any third party to provide the services as requested or as needed on our behalf. These third parties (and any subcontractors) are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent).

**4\. Communicating with you**

We may contact you directly or through a third party service provider regarding products or services you have signed up or purchased from us, such as necessary to deliver transactional or service related communications. We may also contact you with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed based upon legitimate interests. You don’t need to provide consent as a condition to purchase our goods or services. These contacts may include:

  * Email
  * Newsletters
  * Text (SMS) messages
  * Telephone calls
  * Automated phone calls or text messages.

You may also update your subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us and/or our partners by signing into your account and  
visiting “Account Settings” page. 

If we collect information from you in connection with a co-branded offer, it will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the information and whose privacy policy applies.In addition, it will describe any choice options you have in regards to the use and/or sharing of your personal data with a co-branded partner, as well as how to exercise those options.

If you make use of a service that allows you to import contacts (ex. using email marketing services to send emails on your behalf), we will only use the contacts and any other personal information for the requested service. If you believe that anyone has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [ privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com).

**5\. Transfer of Personal Data abroad**

If you utilize our Services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across International borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from one of our global locations outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy.

**6\. Sharing your billing Information with Third parties**  
**6.1 Google Checkout**

If you choose to use Google Checkout to finalize and pay for your order, you will provide your credit card number directly to Google Checkout. Google’s privacy policy will apply to the information you provide on the Google Checkout Website.

**6.2 PayPal**

If you choose to use PayPal to finalize and pay for your order, you will provide your credit card number directly to PayPal. PayPal’s privacy policy will apply to the information you provide on the PayPal Website.

**6.3 Third Party E-Commerce Solutions Provider**

Our shopping cart is hosted by our e-commerce solutions provider. They host our ordering system and collect your billing information directly from you for the purpose of processing your order. This company does not use this information for any other purpose.

**7\. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

We may use cookies, for example to keep track of your preferences and profile information and assist you better. Cookies are also used to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personal information.

**8\. Web beacons**

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

We use a third party to gather information about how you and others use our Web site. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated information to understand and optimize how our site is used.

**9\. Links to Other Websites**

Our Site includes links to other Websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of APPTIVO INC..  
If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Website you visit.

**10\. Security**

The security of your personal information is very important to us. We follow globally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us at [ privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com).

We provide two means for you to make a purchase on our site. You can either use our order from or a third party payment option. If you use our shopping cart, the transmission of sensitive information collected on our order form is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL). If you choose to use a third party payment option to pay for your order, its privacy statement and security practices will apply to your information. We encourage you to read that privacy statement before providing your information.

We use the restricted scopes only to enhance the usage of the features for our users. We’ve explained all the necessity of using the scopes in our blog posts. We never transfer the users’ data and comply with applicable laws. Moreover, the data is stored in an encrypted form. Using the users’ data for advertising will not be permitted at any means. We also prohibit accessing the users’ data by the employees except for resolving technical issues, aggregating data to be made available to the users, and for security purposes. We abide by the rules of GDPR and other applicable laws.

We will retain your information as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, unless otherwise specified by you.

If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [ privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**11\. Usage of 3rd Party Services for Data Sources**

Client uses third parties to gather End User’s data from financial institutions. By using our service, you grant our third-party provider the right, power, and authority to act on your behalf to access and transmit your personal and financial information from the relevant financial institution according to terms of our third-party provider’s privacy policy.

**12\. Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests.**

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (such as subpoena requests), to protect our property and rights or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process. We will also share your information to the extent necessary to comply with ICANN or any ccTLD rules, regulations and policies when you register a domain name with us.

**13\. Website analytics**

We use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as Google Analysis, Facebook Audiences, Facebook Connect, G2Crowd, Drift and PureChat to collect information about how you interact with our website or mobile applications, including what pages you visit, what site you visited prior to visiting our website, how much time you spend on each page, what operating system and web browser you use and network and IP information, and have live chat capability with our visitors.

We use the information provided by these tools to improve our Services. These tools place persistent cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the service provider (ex: Google for Google Analytics). The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service partners on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside.

Though information collected does not include personal data such as name, address, billing information, etc., the information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies. You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through our Cookie Policy or the ‘cookie banners” that may be presented (depending on URL of the website visited) when you first visit our web pages, or by utilizing settings in your browser or third-party tools, such as disconnect, Ghostery, and others.

**14\. Additional Policy Information**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

**Correcting and Updating Your Personal Information**

To review and update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, contact us at [ privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com).

**15\. Age restrictions**

Our Services are available for purchase only for those over the age of 18. Our Services are not targeted to, intended to be consumed by or designed to entice individuals under the age of 18. If you know of or have reason to believe anyone under the age of 18 has provided us with any personal data, please contact us at [ privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com).

**16\. Notification of Privacy Statement Changes**

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices at any time. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**17\. Compliance​ ​process​ ​with​ ​respect​ ​to​ ​international​ ​data​ ​privacy**

Apptivo follows the principles of EU Safe Harbor and other Privacy domains. We don’t collect any data from users for our use, except during the payment process which is pretty typical for all web based services. All other information including a user’s location, email and phone number are needed only for those users to run their business on our platform. For example, if they need to print their address, email and phone number on their proposals or invoices. Apptivo never uses information provided by our users and hence does not mandate users to provide any of that information. All PII and sensitive information are completely optional. Apptivo does not provide any of our client data to third parties. Our policies clearly indicate that clients own their data and we never intend to use their information. We do make an exception to this policy and indicate clearly in our terms of use that we may be forced to share client data with law enforcement in accordance with appropriate legal procedures.

**18\. PRIVACY PRINCIPLES**

Apptivo commits to subject the Personal information covered by this policy to the following principles:

**(1) NOTICE:** Where Apptivo collects Personal information directly from individuals, it will inform them about the purposes for which it collects, stores and processes Personal information about them, and the choices and means, if any,Apptivo offers individuals for limiting the use and disclosure of their Personal information. Notice will be provided in clear and conspicuous language when individuals are first asked to provide Personal information to Apptivo, or as soon as practicable thereafter, and in any event before Apptivo uses the information for a purpose other than that for which it was originally collected.

**(2) CHOICE:** Apptivo will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their Personal information is to be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. Apptivo will provide individuals with reasonable mechanisms to exercise their choices should requisite circumstances arise.

**(3) DATA INTEGRITY AND PURPOSE LIMITATION:** Apptivo will use Personal information only in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. Apptivo will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, complete and current.

**(4) ACCESS AND CORRECTION:** Upon request, Apptivo will grant individuals reasonable access to Personal information that it holds about them. In addition, Apptivo will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. Any employees that desire to review or update their Personal information can do so by contacting their local Human Resources Representative.

**(5) SECURITY:** Apptivo will take reasonable precautions to protect Personal information in its possession from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Apptivo protects data in many ways. Physical security is designed to prevent unauthorized access to database equipment and hard copies of sensitive Personal information. Electronic security measures continuously monitor access to our servers and provide protection from hacking or other unauthorized access from remote locations. This protection includes the use of firewalls, restricted access and encryption technology. Apptivo limits access to Personal information and data to those persons in Apptivo’s organization,that have a specific business purpose for maintaining and processing such Personal information and data. Individuals who have been granted access to Personal information are aware of their responsibilities to protect the security, confidentiality and integrity of that information and have been provided training and instruction on how to do so.

**(6) ACCOUNTABILITY FOR ONWARD TRANSFER:** Apptivo acts as a data controller of Personal Data collected from EU residents and may transfer data onward for processing to other countries, which may not possess Data Protection adequacy levels.

a. To transfer personal information, Apptivo complies with the Notice and Choice Principles of Privacy Shield Framework. Apptivo declares that such data is only processed for limited and specified purposes consistent with the consent provided by the individual.  
b. To transfer personal data outside of EU, Apptivo:

(i) confirms that the transfer of such data is only for limited and specified purposes;  
(ii) is obligated to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Principles;  
(iii) will take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that it effectively processes the personal information transferred in a manner consistent with theits obligations under the Principles;  
(iv) requires to determine that it can no longer meet its obligation to provide the same level of protection as is required by the Principles;  
(v) upon notice,willundertake reasonable and appropriate steps to stop and remediate unauthorized processing; and  
(vi)​ ​will provide a summary or a representative copy of the relevant privacy provisions to the Department upon request.

**(7) RECOURSE, ENFORCEMENT, and LIABILITY:** Apptivo’s participation in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework is subject to investigation and enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission. In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Apptivo commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Data. Data Subjects with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Shield Policy should first contact Apptivo at: [privacy@apptivo.com](mailto:privacy@apptivo.com)

Under certain conditions detailed in the Privacy Shield, Data Subjects may be able to invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel to be created by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission. Apptivo agrees to periodically review and verify its compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, and to remedy any issues arising out of failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles.We commit to investigate and attempt to remedy all valid complaints.  
For more information about binding arbitration, visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

**A. Employee Recourse:** Employees may file a complaint concerning Apptivo’s processing of their Personal Data. Apptivo will take steps to remedy issues arising out of its alleged failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles. Employees may contact Apptivo about complaints regarding Apptivo’s Personal Data practices.

If an Employee’s complaint cannot be resolved through Apptivo’s internal processes, Apptivo will cooperate with the panel of EU data protection authorities established pursuant to the Privacy Shield to address relevant Employee complaints and provide Employees with appropriate recourse free of charge.

**B. Consumer Recourse:** Consumers may file a complaint concerning Apptivo’s processing of their Personal Data. Apptivo will take steps to remedy issues arising out of its alleged failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles. Consumers may contact Apptivo about complaints regarding Apptivo’s Consumer Personal Data practices.

Apptivo also is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.It provide, at no cost to the individual, an independent recourse mechanism by which each individual’s complaints and disputes can be investigated and expeditiously resolved.

Apptivo also has the Data Processing Addendum (“DPA”) which forms part of the End User License and Services Agreement (the “Agreement”) between Customer and Apptivo, to reflect the parties’ agreement about the Processing of Personal Data, when applicable, in accordance with the requirements of Data Protection Laws and Regulations.

If you utilize our Services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from one of our global locations outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy. Apptivo will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure. Apptivo share your personal data with affiliated companies within our corporate family, with third parties with which we have partnered to allow you to integrate their services into our own Services, and with trusted third party service providers as necessary for them to perform services on our behalf.Apptivo will confirm that any third party to which it discloses Personal information will appropriately safeguard the privacy of that Personal information.Examples of appropriate privacy safeguards include: a contract obligating the third party to provide at least the same level of protection as is required by the relevant privacy principles, the third party being subject to EU data protection law, Privacy Shield certification by the third party, or the third party being subject to another European Commission adequacy finding.When Apptivo has knowledge that a third party is using or disclosing Personal information in a manner contrary to this Policy, Apptivo will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure.Apptivo may remain liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if any third parties processes Personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless Apptivo first demonstrates that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage

**19\. DISPUTE RESOLUTION**

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of Personal information should be directed to the Apptivo Data Protection and Privacy Office. Apptivo will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved between Apptivo and the complainant, Apptivo has agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the EU data protection authorities and to cooperate and comply with the Information Commissioner to resolve disputes pursuant to the relevant privacy principles. In some circumstances, complainants may be able to appeal these decisions by invoking binding arbitration. All of these dispute resolution mechanisms are free of charge to you.

**20\. Data Protection Addendum**

This Data Protection Addendum (DPA) forms part of the Apptivo Terms of Use (“Principal Agreement”) between (i) Apptivo acting on its behalf and as agent for each Apptivo Affiliate, and (ii) Customer acting on its behalf and as agent for each Company Affiliate. The terms used in this Addendum shall have the meanings outlined in this Addendum.You may review our full Data Protection Addendum (DPA) at <https://www.apptivo.com/dpa/>

### Contact Information

You can contact us about this privacy statement by writing or email us at the address below:

APPTIVO INC.

38750 Paseo Padre Pkwy,

Suite #A2, Fremont,  
CA 94536,  
United States
